

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211





# ARIVAZHAKAN PALANISAMY (1) Featured | |



Senior System Analyst seeking roles in Project

Management, IT Operations, Incident Management, Production

Support .Service

Management, Configuration Management, Software installation, Asset

management, Global Access

Management, Python, UNIX, C++, J2EE, TIBCO

Current Designation: Senior System Analyst Current Company: Emirates Telecommunications

Corporation

Current Location: United Arab Emirates

Pref. Location: United Arab Emirates (UAE), United Kingdom

(UK).United States (US)

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: System Analyst Industry: Telcom/ISP Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior System Analyst, Project Management, IT Operations, Incident Management, Production Support, Service

Total Experience: 25 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: MS/MSc(Science) [Statistics]

Management, Configuration Management, Software installation, Asset management, Global Access

Management, Python, UNIX, C++, TIBCO (EAI), J2EE

Verified: Email - id

Last Modified: 22-Jan-21 Last Active: 22-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

### **Summary**

IT professional, offering over 25 years of experience in Operations, Team Management, Computing Application Architecture, Design, Development and Business Application Operation Support of Enterprise Applications & Integration using TIBCO Middleware Messaging and TIBCO EAI products; domain expertise in Telecom Experienced in TIBCO Administration, TIBCO Business works, TIBCO Enterprise Message Service, TIBCO iProcess, TIBCO Hawk, TIBCO Software installation and upgrade in SOLARIS and UNIX

Recognized for managing high pressure missions, innovating and implementing solutions in complex projects and critical deliveries; bagged Best Employer

Award in Service Fulfilment Team

Familiar with Python Programming, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning & Deep Learning 5G Mobile Networks / Software Defined Networking and OpenFlow ensuring that the goals of the Incident/Change/Problem Management process are achieved; restoring normal service as soon as possible

Skills in SDLC including Design

# **Work Experience**

Emirates Telecommunications Corporation as Senior System Analyst Mar 2007 to Till Date

Growth Path:

Mar'2007 - Dec'2011 as Software Specialist / Middleware, Abu Dhabi

Jan'2012 - Aug'2017 as Administrator, Abu Dhabi

Aug'2017 - till date as Senior System Analyst (In-Charging & Integration Operations Support), Sharjah Kev Result Areas:

Managing all aspects of IT Operations including Service Level Management, Compliance (Systems Operations), Back-

 ${\it M} an agement \& Contingency Planning, IT Asset Management and IT Infrastructure Support {\it Management} (Management) and {$ 

Monitoring SOP validation; marinating KPIs by avoiding Service Fulfillment rejection; preparing daily report with analysis, governance call-weekly/ bi-weekly on all the projects
Playing a key role in recruiting, training, performance management, employee development & engagement; motivating

& training

team to achieve smooth functionality of operations

Managing weekly deployments and releases for the Service Fulfillment System



# **Important**

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Conducting regular meeting with stakeholders to understand on the project updates, metrics reporting; delivering support tasks

& ad-hoc activities

Resolving Customer Complaints / Tickets / UCMS / SD and maintaining the KPI

Spearheading end-to-end Production Support and Maintenance project activities to provide excellent support to internal and

external clients

Identifying issues & risks in a timely manner; developing / implementing appropriate mitigation & contingency plans Improving software deployment to ensure iterative releases and rapid deployment of updates to the customers across

platforms; defining application support standards and processes and writing the related documentation

Coordinating with cross-functional teams for critical issue resolution on a regular basis, resolving client escalation and high-priority

cases; providing solutions of client queries on the application via calls, email, chats thereby resulting in achievement of customer

satisfaction matrices

Supervising high severity incidents to ensure service availability with minimal delay and working towards ensuring smooth

operations of the infrastructure environment

Following & implementing policies & procedures for disaster recovery and data archiving to ensure effective protectionand integrity

of data assets

Providing post-implementation, application maintenance and enhancement support and problem solutions Key Result Areas: (Administrator)

Deployed 500 Plus TIBCO BW in various domains and Work Force Management (WFM) system

Released 100 Plus TIBCO iProcess Procedures for Work Force Management (WFM) Systems

Maintained and supporting the systems under Service Fulfillment Domain / In-Operation & Support

Resolved rejected messages for GSM/IN/PSTN/TOLL Free/BBNET/IPCONNECT services; coordinated with cross-

functional teams

to maintain operational KPIs

Analyzed root cause of rejections and got them resolved in TAT; managed the migration of SYMSOFT to OPENMIND for SMSC

Provided operational support for network/planned/un planned outages

Prepared scripts and gave configuration details to the Service Assurance Center Team for alarm configuration

Spearheaded many Reconciliation Projects between Networks Element and Systems

Key Result Areas: (Software Specialist / Middleware)

Played pivotal role in development of TAP 3.11.12 Roaming System; maintained & supported the same

Converted CDR call logs into TAPOUT & TAPIN files and submitted to the data clearance center; sent it to billing system as

required

Coordinated with EDCH for the TAPIN and TAPOUT and call disputes for the customers

Contributed in development of Web Services and other interfaced applications like for e-Shop Application and CBCM system

#### Wipro Technologies (I) Ltd as Technical Lead

Oct 2006 to Dec 2006

Project: H3G, UK Client

Contributed in the high level designing

#### Ness Technologies (India) Ltd. as Software Engineer

Feb 2004 to Mar 2006

Project: Portal TelcoOne Integrator for Siebel eCommunication For Portal

Environment: Sun Solaris v2.6, Windows NT, TIB/Business works 5.2, Siebel 7.7, UAN 4.1 and TIB/SmartMapper 5.1.3

Project: Simulation Of SONET (SOS)

Environment: C++, GTK-- under Red Hat Linux 7.0

Project: Simulation of Telephone Switching System

Environment: C++, GTK-- under Red Hat Linux 7.0

Project: Universal Studio's Theme Park for PDA's and WAP phones

Environment: WML, Nokia WAP Toolkit 2.0, WAPLite under Windows NT Server 4.0

Project: WAP Online Shopping

Environment: WML, Java servlets Under Windows 98, Nokia WAP Toolkit 2.0, WAPLite gateway, Apache Web server

Project: Computerized Video Kiosk

Environment: Visual Basic 6.0 under Windows 98, MS-SQL Server

Project: Time and Attendance Monitoring System

Environment: C under SCO UNIX System V Release 3.0ss

^ Back to Top

### **Education**

UG: B.Sc (Statistics) from Bharathidasan University in 1992

PG: MS/M.Sc(Science) (Statistics) from Madras University in 1994

^ Back to Top

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
SCO UNIX System V Release 3.0	
Red Hat Linux 7.1, Sun Solaris V5.1	
MS-DOS 6.22, Windows 2000	
WIN NT	
C, C++,Java and J2EE	

TIBCO Administrator 5.6
TIBCO Business Works 5.7.2
TIBCO iProcess 11.2
TIBCO Hawk 5.6, UAN 2.0/4.1
Smart Mapper 5.1.2
XML, XSD, Web Services, SOAP
TIBCO Enterprise Message Service 6.0
Siebel 7.7, Siebel Tools 7.7
SQL Server 7.0
Rational Rose 2000, GTK+, GTK
OOAD, UML
TCP/IP, X25, ATM, SS7, SONET/SDH
ISDN, Frame Relay, GSM, WAP
Bluetooth, VOIP, 3G

^ Back to Top

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
english	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
Tamil	Proficient	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

# **Affirmative Action**

# **Work Authorization**

Category: **General**Physically Challenged: **No** 

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.